Gerald R. Gill Papers MS170
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Correspondence, circa 1981 -- 2007; MS170.003; 8.4 Linear Feet 7 record cartons; 266 Megabytes; 17,427 Digital Object(s)
  - Paper mail, circa 1981 -- 2007; MS170.003.001; 8.4 Linear Feet 7 record cartons.
    - Correspondence, 1991 -- 2000, undated; MS170.003.004.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1991, 2000 -- 2003, undated; MS170.003.004.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1991 -- 2001, undated; MS170.003.004.00017; 2 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 20-21)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1991, 2001 -- 2007, undated; MS170.003.004.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1991, 2003 -- 2005, undated; MS170.003.004.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 1991 -- 2005; MS170.003.005.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1992 -- 1995; MS170.003.005.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1992 -- 1997, undated; MS170.003.005.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1993 -- 1994, undated; MS170.003.005.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1993 -- 1994, undated; MS170.003.005.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence on Henry Hampton, 1993 -- 1995; MS170.003.005.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1993 -- 1994, 2004, undated; MS170.003.005.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and enclosures from the Golden Key National Honor Society, 1994; MS170.003.005.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1994; MS170.003.005.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1994 -- 1996; MS170.003.005.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1994 -- 1996, undated; MS170.003.005.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1994 -- 1996, undated; MS170.003.005.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence and enclosures on events, circa 1994 -- 1997; MS170.003.005.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1994 -- 1997, undated; MS170.003.005.00014; 2 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
    - Correspondence, 1995 -- 1996, undated; MS170.003.005.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, enclosures, and newspapers on Gerald R. Gill, 1995 -- 1996, undated; MS170.003.006.00001; 4 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1995 -- 1996, undated; MS170.003.006.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1995 -- 1998, undated; MS170.003.006.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1995 -- 1998, undated; MS170.003.006.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Joiner Center newsletter, 1996; MS170.003.006.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1996, 2005, undated; MS170.003.006.00006; 2 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence, 1996 -- 1997, undated; MS170.003.006.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1995 -- 1997, undated; MS170.003.006.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1996 -- 1997, undated; MS170.003.006.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 1996 -- 1999, undated; MS170.003.006.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1998; MS170.003.006.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1998 -- 2003; MS170.003.006.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 1998 -- 2006, undated; MS170.003.006.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Brochures on I'll Make Me a World, circa 1999; MS170.003.006.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1999, undated; MS170.003.006.00015; 2 Folder(s) (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
    - Correspondence on teaching assistantships, 1999; MS170.003.007.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1999 -- 2000, undated; MS170.003.007.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence on the EPIIC seminar, 1999 -- 2000; MS170.003.007.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1999 -- 2000, undated; MS170.003.007.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1999 -- 2000, undated; MS170.003.007.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1999 -- 2002, undated; MS170.003.007.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 1992 -- 2002, undated; MS170.003.007.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence about Tufts alumni, 1999 -- 2003, undated; MS170.003.007.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1999, 2004; MS170.003.007.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1999, 2004; MS170.003.007.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1999 -- 2007, undated; MS170.003.007.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 2000; MS170.003.009.00002; 4 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 5-8)
    - Correspondence, 2000; MS170.003.007.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 2000; MS170.003.007.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 2000, undated; MS170.003.007.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 2000, undated; MS170.003.007.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 2000 -- 2002, undated; MS170.003.007.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 2000 -- 2005, undated; MS170.003.007.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 2000 -- 2006; MS170.003.007.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 2000 -- 2006, undated; MS170.003.007.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and enclosures on the Tufts Black Alumni Association reunion, 2000, undated; MS170.003.007.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence on the Tufts Black Alumni Association reunion, circa 2000; MS170.003.007.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence on the Tufts Black Alumni Association reunion, 2000, undated; MS170.003.007.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 2001; MS170.003.009.00003; 3 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
    - Correspondence on the Tufts Black Alumni Association reunion, 2001 -- 2003; MS170.003.007.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, 2001; MS170.003.007.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 2001, undated; MS170.003.007.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence and enclosures on the American Civil Liberties: The Roger Baldwin Years collection, 2001; MS170.003.007.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, 2001; MS170.003.007.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence on Howard Thurman: In Search of Common Ground, 2001, undated; MS170.003.007.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence and notes, 2001 -- 2003, undated; MS170.003.007.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence and enclosures on Capital Partners of Education, 2001-2004, MS170.003.007.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Correspondence, 2002; MS170.003.007.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 2002, undated; MS170.003.007.00032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Correspondence, 2002; MS170.003.007.00033; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - Correspondence, 2002; MS170.003.009.00004; 3 Folder(s) (Box 9, Folder 12-14)
    - Correspondence, 2002 -- 2003, undated; MS170.003.007.00034; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 2002 -- 2006, undated; MS170.003.007.00035; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Correspondence, 2002 -- 2007, undated; MS170.003.007.00036; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Correspondence, 2003; MS170.003.010.00001; 4 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 1-4)
    - Correspondence, 2003, undated; MS170.003.007.00037; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Correspondence, 2003, undated; MS170.003.007.00038; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence from Lyle Mogs, 2003; MS170.003.007.00039; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Correspondence on Alaska Highway, 2003, undated; MS170.003.007.00040; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence, 2003 -- 2004; MS170.003.007.00041; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence, 2003, 2005, undated; MS170.003.007.00042; 1 Folder(s) (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence, 2003 -- 2006, undated; MS170.003.008.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 2003 -- 2007; MS170.003.008.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 2004; MS170.003.010.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence and fliers, 2004; MS170.003.008.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 2004; MS170.003.008.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence on Southwest School, 2004; MS170.003.008.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 2004, undated; MS170.003.008.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 2004 -- 2005, undated; MS170.003.008.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 2004, 2007; MS170.003.008.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 2004 -- 2006; MS170.003.008.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 2005; MS170.003.008.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 2005; MS170.003.008.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 2005; MS170.003.010.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 2005, undated; MS170.003.008.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 2005, undated; MS170.003.008.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 2005, undated; MS170.003.008.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 2005, undated; MS170.003.008.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 2005 -- 2007, undated; MS170.003.008.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, 2006; MS170.003.010.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 2006, undated; MS170.003.008.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, 2006, undated; MS170.003.008.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 2006, undated; MS170.003.008.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 2006 -- 2007, undated; MS170.003.008.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence, 2007; MS170.003.010.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 2007, undated; MS170.003.008.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence, 2007; MS170.003.008.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence and enclosures, 2007, undated; MS170.003.008.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.003.008.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.003.008.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.003.008.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.003.008.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.003.008.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.003.008.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Correspondence, circa 1980 -- 2007; MS170.003.010.00006; 7 Folder(s) (Box 10, Folder 9-15)
  - Electronic mail, 1997 -- 2005; MS170.003.002; 15,505 Digital Object(s) There are 15,505 email messages from Gill's Tufts email account, both sent and received.; 1,922 Digital Object(s) There are 1,922 attachments in Gill's email, 471 of which are images.; 266 Megabytes
    This subseries contains Gerald Gill's Tufts email, which covers the years 1997-2005. The majority of the email is related to university business - teaching, departmental business, and communications with students, past and present. Gill's most frequent correspondents were his colleagues in the history department.
    Emails containing information about official university business, such as committee work, have been restricted for 20 years. Emails containing resumes, CVs, and student recommendations have been restricted for 75 years.
    Email will be made available on a DCA laptop in the reading room only.
- Events, 1964 -- 2006; MS170.004; 6 Linear Feet 4 full record cartons, 1 partial record carton, 1 partial oversize box
  This series is arranged in three sub-series: General Events; Tufts Events; and Another Light on the Hill Exhibit.
  This series documents events Gill planned, attended, or was interested in. Materials include posters, fliers, promotional materials, registration packets, conference handouts, planning documentation, and a small amount of related correspondence and research.
  Sub-series 1, General Events, contains information on conferences, lectures, movies, and documentary showings that were not held at or sponsored by Tufts. There is a small amount of material related to Gill's work on Eyes on the Prize and the teaching materials created to accompany the documentary. Seminars at the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library in Boston are also represented in this subseries.
  Sub-series 2, Tufts Events, contains information on lectures, movies, fundraisers, social mixers, and other Tufts community events, including lectures given or moderated by Gill. Black alumni events and many events given by or related to the Black community at Tufts are represented in this sub-series.
  Sub-series 3, Another Light on the Hill Exhibit, includes fliers, postcards, guest books, and research materials related to an exhibit Gill created highlighting the accomplishments of Black students at Tufts. Exhibit-related research contains some photocopies of yearbooks and other archival material, which while not unique, were retained due to their value as a body of research.
  - General events, 1964 -- 2006; MS170.004.002; 2.1 Linear Feet 2 partial record cartons, 1 full record carton
    This sub-series is open for research.
    This sub-series is arranged chronologically.
    Sub-series 1, General Events, contains information on conferences, lectures, movies, and documentary showings that were not held at or sponsored by Tufts. There is a small amount of material related to Gill's work on "Eyes on the Prize" and the teaching materials created to accompany the documentary. Seminars at the John F. Kennedy Presidential Library in Boston are also represented in this subseries.
    - "Negro History Workshop", 1964; MS170.004.002.012.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - State of Black America press conference, 1981; MS170.004.002.012.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - West Medford Community Center, 1986 -- 1987; MS170.004.002.012.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Conferences, 1987; MS170.004.002.012.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Events, 1987 -- 1989; MS170.004.002.012.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Eyes on the Prize archive project, 1987 -- 1988; MS170.004.002.012.00023; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Eyes on the Prize meeting, 1988 -- 1989; MS170.004.002.012.00024; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Dartmouth College civil rights conference, 1989; MS170.004.002.012.00025; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Eyes on the Prize II conference, 1989; MS170.004.002.012.00026; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Eyes on the Prize Educator's Institute, 1990; MS170.004.002.012.00027; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Eyes on the Prize teaching materials, 1990; MS170.004.002.012.00028; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Events, 1990 -- 1999; MS170.004.002.012.00029; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - The Black Educational Movement in Boston conference, 1993; MS170.004.002.012.00030; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Roy Wilkins Symposium, 1995; MS170.004.002.012.00031; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - MIT Technology Day, 1995; MS170.004.002.012.00032; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Birmingham Civil Rights Institute, 1995; MS170.004.002.012.00033; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Institute of Affirmative Action conference, 1995; MS170.004.002.012.00034; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Blacks in Boston: The Caribbean Connection conference, 1995 -- 1996; MS170.004.002.012.00035; 1 Folder(s) (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Teaching Boston History workshop, 1996; MS170.004.002.013.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Discussion group with Namibian officials, 1996; MS170.004.002.013.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy Library events, 1998; MS170.004.002.013.00003; 2 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 3-4)
    - Kennedy Library civil rights events, 1998; MS170.004.002.013.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy Library civil rights conference, circa 1998; MS170.004.002.013.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - National Historical Publications and Records Commission grant meetings, 1999; MS170.004.002.013.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - James Armistad Commemorative Stamp Project, 1999; MS170.004.002.013.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - "This Far By Faith," documentary, 1999; MS170.004.002.013.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Teachers as Scholars, 2000; MS170.004.002.013.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - New England Historical Association Conference, 2000; MS170.004.002.013.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Long Road to Justice: African American Experience in the Massachusetts Courts, 2000; MS170.004.002.013.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Roundtable Advisory Meeting, Basketball: The Story of the Game, 2000; MS170.004.002.013.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Events, 2000 -- 2002; MS170.004.002.013.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - American Historical Association meeting, 2000 -- 2001; MS170.004.002.013.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - The Black Educational Movement in Boston, 2001; MS170.004.002.013.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Documentary screenings featuring Black soldiers, 2001; MS170.004.002.013.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - "This Far By Faith," documentary, 2001; MS170.004.002.013.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Kennedy Library events, 2001; MS170.004.002.013.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - "Come and Gone" and "Ma Rainey's Black Bottom," plays, 2002 -- 2003; MS170.004.002.013.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Primary Source, Making Freedom II Summer Institute, 2002; MS170.004.002.013.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Massachusetts Historical Society, Immigration and Urban History Seminar Series, 2002; MS170.004.002.013.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - "Flyin' West" and "Ma Rainey's Black Bottom," plays, 2002; MS170.004.002.014.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - "Cambridge Uncovered" studio taping, 2002; MS170.004.002.014.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Kennedy Library events, 2002; MS170.004.002.014.00003; 2 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
    - Lafayette Alumnus-in-Residence week and Presidency of Harry S. Truman Panel, 2002; MS170.004.002.014.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Kennedy Library, "Teaching American History: The Civil Rights Struggle Through the Kennedy Years", 2003; MS170.004.002.014.00005; 2 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 6-7)
    - March on Washington 40th Anniversary, 2003; MS170.004.002.014.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Museum of Afro-American History, "Black Books: the First African American Authors", 2003; MS170.004.002.014.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - "This Far By Faith," documentary, 2003; MS170.004.002.014.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Events, 2003 -- 2005; MS170.004.002.014.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Kennedy Library, "Teaching American History: The Civil Rights Struggle Through the Kennedy Years", 2004; MS170.004.002.014.00010; 2 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 12-13)
    - Iraq War documentaries, 2004; MS170.004.002.014.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - New York University, "Brown Plus Fifty: A Renewed Agenda for Social Justice", 2004; MS170.004.002.014.00012; 2 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 15-16)
    - Brown v. Board Decision: 50th Anniversary, public meeting and forum, 2004; MS170.004.002.014.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Impact of the Brown decision on American Education and Society conference, 2004; MS170.004.002.014.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Organization of American Historians panel, 2004; MS170.004.002.014.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - "Making Freedom: African Americans in United States History" and "African Americans and the Making of America", 2004; MS170.004.002.014.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Paul Robeson conference, 2005; MS170.004.002.014.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Massachusetts Historical Society, Immigration and Urban History Seminar Series, 2006; MS170.004.002.014.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Kennedy Library civil rights conference, planning materials, 2006; MS170.004.002.014.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Kennedy Library, "The Civil Rights Movement in Boston", 2006; MS170.004.002.014.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Tufts events, 1978 -- 2006; MS170.004.001; 1.5 Linear Feet 1 full record carton, 1 partial record carton
    - Events, 1978 -- 1979; MS170.004.001.011.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Events, 1984 -- 1989; MS170.004.001.011.00002; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - James Farmer lecture, 1987; MS170.004.001.011.00003; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Ronald Blackburn scholarship fundraisers, 1987 -- 1992; MS170.004.001.011.00004; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Events and clippings, 1987 -- 1996; MS170.004.001.011.00005; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - African American Center events, 1987 -- 1999; MS170.004.001.011.00006; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Concern, Protest, and Commitment, exhibit, comment book, 1989; MS170.004.001.011.00007; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Trouble in Mind," play, 1987; MS170.004.001.011.00008; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Beyond the Barricades forum, 1990; MS170.004.001.011.00009; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Events, circa 1990 -- 1995; MS170.004.001.048.00001; 1 Folder(s) (Box 48, Box 1)
    - Jester Hairston, concerts memorial services and obituaries, 1990 -- 2000; MS170.004.001.011.00010; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Tree planting memorial for Black alumni with obituaries, 1990 -- 2001; MS170.004.001.011.00011; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Black Alumni Association Homecoming Reunion, 1992; MS170.004.001.011.00012; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Events, 1995 -- 1999; MS170.004.001.011.00013; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Hunter, Gregory A. memorial service, 1995; MS170.004.001.011.00014; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Buttrick, Glenn W. memorial service, 1997; MS170.004.001.011.00015; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Events, 1997; MS170.004.001.011.00016; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Events, 1998 -- 2003; MS170.004.001.011.00017; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Events, 1999; MS170.004.001.011.00018; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Events, 1999 -- 2000; MS170.004.001.011.00019; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Black Alumni Weekend, planning materials, 2000; MS170.004.001.011.00020; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Black Alumni Weekend, list of alums, 2000; MS170.004.001.011.00021; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Black Alumni Weekend, registration packet materials, 2000; MS170.004.001.011.00022; 1 Folder(s) (Box 11, Folder 22)